nestpensions.org.uk 2019-03-31

# Privacy policy

National Employment Savings Trust (NEST) Corporation ('we' or 'us') takes your privacy seriously. Please read this Privacy policy, our privacy information notices below, help areas (when interacting with our website) and our Cookies policy. Together they explain our data protection policy and describe how we’ll use any personal data we collect from you or that is provided to us.

In May 2018 the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 and the Data Protection Act 2018 (jointly referred to as ‘Data Protection legislation’) came into force. In most instances, NEST Corporation is the controller for the processing of personal information we hold about you. More information on this can be found in the relevant individual privacy information notice below.

NEST Corporation is registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office (Registration number: Z2343426).

Our Data Protection Officer is our Chief Risk Officer, whose office can be contacted at [dpo@nestcorporation.org.uk](mailto:dpo@nestcorporation.org.uk).

## Change to Data protection law

Legislation governing the use of your personal information has changed. In May 2018, the EU General Data Protection Regulation came into force and the UK Data Protection Act 2018 was passed.  You can read about the changes on the ICO’s [website](https://ico.org.uk/).

In line with the above changes, NEST has updated this policy and has prepared privacy information notices (see links provided below) so that you can find out how we use your personal information. 

In addition, NEST has prepared this frequently asked questions document for anyone seeking additional information on data protection legislation not contained in the relevant privacy notices below.

Our privacy information notices are listed below under titles which relate specifically to who the information applies to.

## Privacy Information Notices

  * I am a NEST member
  * I am a NEST member delegate
  * I am a NEST employer delegate, or a NEST connector delegate
  * I am an initiator of an employer account or a NEST connector
  * I am a third party (such as ex-spouse, beneficiary of a member, doctor, etc.)
  * I am applying for a vacancy at NEST
  * I am browsing your website

## Changes to the policy

We may change our Privacy policy from time to time. If, or when any material changes are made, we will let you know about them. We’ll also include them here.

## Other third party websites

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to and from third-party websites, including those of our partner networks and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites may have their own privacy policies. We don’t accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## Security and safe storage of your personal information

The security of your personal information is very important to us and we take this matter very seriously.  We’ll use appropriate procedures and security features to process and protect your information.  We have in place a robust framework to ensure the security of your information.

The information security management systems operated by NEST Corporation, our scheme administrator and our IT managed services provider are all independently certified to the ISO 27001 standard. This gives us assurance that our systems and processes are robust and helps protect your personal information.

We may monitor the use and content of emails, calls and secure messages sent from and received by us so that we can, for instance, identify and take legal action against unlawful or improper use of our systems. The main examples of unlawful or improper use are attempting to impersonate NEST Corporation, the transmission of computer viruses and attempts to prevent this website or its services from working.

## How can you access, correct your information and withdraw consent?

You’re able to find out how to correct the information we hold about you, or change your preferences relating to marketing communications from NEST and withdraw your consent at any time by clicking on the appropriate section below:

  * I am a NEST member
  * I am a NEST member delegate
  * I am a NEST employer delegate, or a NEST connector delegate
  * I am an initiator of an employer account or a NEST connector
  * I am a third party (such as ex-spouse, beneficiary of a member, doctor, etc.)
  * I am applying for a vacancy at NEST
  * I am browsing your website

Depending on the circumstances, you may also have the right to:

  * request erasure of personal information we hold about you
  * request restriction of processing of such information
  * object to the processing of such information
  * request a copy of such information in a portable format

If you have concerns about the way we handle your personal data, you can contact us (please see details below) or directly contact the [ICO](https://www.ico.org.uk/concerns/).

## Freedom of information

NEST Corporation is a public authority in its role as a public corporation

The Freedom of Information Act 2000 gives any person of any nationality, anywhere in the world, the right of access to official information held by public authorities.

Visit our Support and resources section to find out more about what information NEST Corporation publishes, how we respond to information requests and how we handle complaints.

If you'd like to request information about NEST Corporation, please read the [FOI guidance notes for applicants (PDF)](http://www.nestpensions.org.uk/schemeweb/NestWeb/includes/public/docs/foia_notes_applicants,PDF.pdf).

To make a request for information under the Freedom of Information Act please send your request to [secretariat@nestcorporation.org.uk](mailto:secretariat@nestcorporation.org.uk) or to:

Freedom of Information requests  
Secretariat  
10 South Colonnade  
Canary Wharf  
London  
E14 4PU

## Comments and questions

You can send any queries and comments about this Privacy policy by email to [secretariat@nestcorporation.org.uk](mailto:secretariat@nestcorporation.org.uk) or by mail to Secretariat, NEST Corporation, 10 South Colonnade, Canary Wharf, London, E14 4PU. Please note that if you email this address, or another specific address on the website, it may not always be possible for us to deal directly with your enquiry. We may need to pass this to another government agency to fulfil your request or answer your query.

Last updated: December 2018
